Okay, so maybe you want to do a little
more than just loop over this array of
Justice League members. Maybe you want
to know who the least efficient
superheroes are. Maybe you want to
filter it to just those who have caught
less than five villains in the last
month. So what you can do is rather than
doing a for loop, you can use a built-in
function um where you say Justice League
dot filter. What filter does is it
accepts a function that returns true or
false on whether or not you should keep
the item. So, for example, if we wrote a
function here called less than five and
let it take in an array,
then we could say if array
at the three position, um, this last
one, if array at the three position is
less than five,
um, then I'm going to say let return val
equal
false. If they're if they have less than
five, then we're going to set the return
value equal to true. Um, so we're
automatically assuming they have more
than five. If we find out they have less
than five, then we're going to change
that value to they have less than five.
And then we're going to return the
return value. So now we have a function
that takes in an array and finds out if
the third position in that array is less
than five and returns value accordingly.
All right. Well, let's test this. So, um
I happen to know that Ray Palmer is in
the 10th position of this array. So, um
if I alert um
Justice League, sorry, if I alert
less than five
at in the Justice League at the 10
position, then I should get false
because he or sorry, I should get true
because he has caught less than five
villains. If I copy this line to the
next line and do it for position zero,
which is Superman, Superman has caught
12 villains. Um, then I should get
false. So, let's come over here to our
running code and I get true for the
first one and false for the second one.
So, that means that our function works.
So, what we want to do is we want to go
justice.filter
and then we want to pass in less than
five. So if we save this and
um we console.log
our Justice League our filter Justice
League for less than five we get true
false.
And if we inspect and look at our
console
did I save that after I changed that to
console log? We'll save that true false.
And we here we can see on our console
that we have um our array which is
limited down to just those Justice
League members who caught less than five
villains this month which is pretty
cool. But I don't know about you, I'm
not planning to use this very specific
function anywhere else. This is a less
than five function and it takes in an
array and because of the way I've
programmed it, it needs to be an array
that's set up like one of the items in
the Justice League list. So, that's a
lot of code for a function that I'm only
going to use in one spot. Yes, it gets
called multiple times, but I'm only
using it in one spot. Um,
so let's see if we can simplify this
function down. Um, I'm going to say
const less than five
equals
a function that takes in an array
and
it really returns true if this is less
than five
or false if it's greater than five. So
if we simplify that, we could say return
and we could say array at the three
position is less than five. Um and if it
is, then we want to return true.
Otherwise, we want to return false.
And that's one way to write it. Or we
could simplify this down if all we're
doing is we're returning the result of
this. So if it's less than five, then
that returns true. This already
evaluates down to true. So maybe we
could just return that.
Um we can just return array is less than
five. So that will say if the array at
the three position is less than five,
return true. Well, anytime that you're
just returning the result of an
evaluation, you can put it on one line.
So I could say const less than five,
and I'll delete this one. And I can set
it equal to a function that takes in an
array and returns
if the array the three position is less
than five. So now I've broken that down
onto one line. Well, if you're going to
break it all the way down onto one line
like that, then you can just write it
directly in this filter because we could
create remember a function just needs
parenthesis
the arrow and something it returns. So
here in filter we're going to do
parenthesis. We're going to take an
array.
Going to use the arrow and we're going
to return array at the three position is
less than five.
Now we don't need those anymore. So what
we're saying is in this filter we want
to take every item out of this Justice
League array and we want to run it
through this function. What does this
function do? Well, it takes in the array
that we give it um looks at the three
position in that array and determines if
it's less than five. If it is, it keeps
it in this Justice League array. If it's
not, it removes it. And so, if we save
this and we come over here, we can see
our code is still working. We'll even
reload the page a couple times just to
prove it. Our code is still working and
we've successfully filtered down to just
those members of the Justice League um
that are
not catching as many villains.
And that concludes this video. Thanks
for watching.